<chapter><?dbhtml filename="legal.html" ?>
<title>Legal Acknowledgment</title>
<para>This program is bundled with these 3rd-party components.</para>

<sect2><title>MBPreferencesModule</title>
<programlisting><![CDATA[
Copyright (c) 2008 Matthew Ball - http://www.mattballdesign.com

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person
obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation
files (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without
restriction, including without limitation the rights to use,
copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following
conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be
included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES
OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND
NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT
HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY,
WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR
OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
]]>
</programlisting>
</sect2>

<sect2><title>NSImage+QuickLook</title>
<programlisting><![CDATA[
License Agreement for Source Code provided by Matt Gemmell

This software is supplied to you by Matt Gemmell in
consideration of your agreement to the following terms, and
your use, installation, modification or redistribution of this
software constitutes acceptance of these terms. If you do not
agree with these terms, please do not use, install, modify or
redistribute this software.

In consideration of your agreement to abide by the following
terms, and subject to these terms, Matt Gemmell grants you a
personal, non-exclusive license, to use, reproduce, modify and
redistribute the software, with or without modifications, in
source and/or binary forms; provided that if you redistribute
the software in its entirety and without modifications, you
must retain this notice and the following text and disclaimers
in all such redistributions of the software, and that in all
cases attribution of Matt Gemmell as the original author of the
source code shall be included in all such resulting software
products or distributions.  Neither the name, trademarks,
service marks or logos of Matt Gemmell or Magic Aubergine may
be used to endorse or promote products derived from the
software without specific prior written permission from Matt
Gemmell. Except as expressly stated in this notice, no other
rights or licenses, express or implied, are granted by Matt
Gemmell herein, including but not limited to any patent rights
that may be infringed by your derivative works or by other
works in which the software may be incorporated.

The software is provided by Matt Gemmell on an "AS IS" basis.
MATT GEMMELL AND MAGIC AUBERGINE MAKE NO WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF
NON-INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
PURPOSE, REGARDING THE SOFTWARE OR ITS USE AND OPERATION ALONE
OR IN COMBINATION WITH YOUR PRODUCTS.

IN NO EVENT SHALL MATT GEMMELL OR MAGIC AUBERGINE BE LIABLE FOR
ANY SPECIAL, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES
(INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS
OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS
INTERRUPTION) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE, REPRODUCTION,
MODIFICATION AND/OR DISTRIBUTION OF THE SOFTWARE, HOWEVER
CAUSED AND WHETHER UNDER THEORY OF CONTRACT, TORT (INCLUDING
NEGLIGENCE), STRICT LIABILITY OR OTHERWISE, EVEN IF MATT
GEMMELL OR MAGIC AUBERGINE HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY
OF SUCH DAMAGE.
]]>
</programlisting>
</sect2>


<sect2><title>Joseph Wain - Eye icon</title>
<ulink url="http://penandthink.com/">Pen and Think - Joseph Wain</ulink>
<programlisting><![CDATA[
Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 United States (+ Attribution)
]]>
</programlisting>
</sect2>

</chapter>