<chapter xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"><?dbhtml filename="preface.html" ?>
<title>Preface</title>

<section>
<title>Introduction</title>
<para>When using Newton Commander, always remember that the keyboard is quicker than the mouse.</para>

<mediaobject>
  <imageobject>
    <imagedata fileref="images/keyboard.png" format="PNG"/>
  </imageobject>
  <textobject>
    <phrase>Original Mac Keyboard</phrase>
  </textobject>
</mediaobject>

</section>


<section>
<title>About the Documentation</title>
<para>This program contains 3 sample projects that should be the first thing you toy with, before you move on to bigger projects. They are simple and good looking. Further more there is a 27 page PDF that describes in great detail how these projects work. This should give you an idea what this "building-block" concept is all about.</para>
    
<para>It's just a fraction of what GraphicDesignerToolbox can do.</para>

<para>When you are ready to proceed, then visit the <ulink url="http://graphicdesignertoolbox.com/download-sample-projects">sample section on the homepage</ulink> and see for yourself how BIG projects looks like. There are a lot of building blocks to get familiar with, for this reason they have been tagged: easy, medium, hard. It's like a computer game - if you are a new and you play on a hard level then you are more likely to die a quick death. Start out by mastering the easy building blocks, then move on to medium and finally pick hard.</para>
</section>


<section>
<title>Terminology</title>
<para>Terms that might be a source of misunderstanding.</para>
    
<segmentedlist>
<?dbhtml list-presentation="table"?>
<segtitle>Term</segtitle>
<segtitle>Explanation</segtitle>
<seglistitem>
    <seg>Cursor</seg>
    <seg>The cursor can be moved up/down using the up/down arrow keys.</seg>
</seglistitem>
<seglistitem>
    <seg>Panel</seg>
    <seg>NC has two panels (dual-pane). The left panel and the right panel.</seg>
</seglistitem>
</segmentedlist>
    
</section>


<section>
<title>Welcome to Newton Commander</title>

<para>When using Newton Commander, always remember that the keyboard is quicker than the mouse.
On a Macintosh such essential keys as F9, F10, F11 and F12 are used as Exposé, Show Desktop and Dashboard shortcuts.  I've changed all the Exposé and Dashboard shortcuts in System Preferences > Dashboard and Exposé.    
</para>

</section>


<section>
<title>What is Newton Commander</title>
<subtitle>It's a file manager!</subtitle>

<para>When you start the NC for the first time you will a window on your screen, looking like this:
    
</para>

<para>
Newton Commander is a lot like Norton Commander and Total Commander.
    
</para>

<para>It's inspired by Norton Commander. It's for Mac. Since 
Isaac Newton sat under an apple tree when he discovered
gravity, it's highly relevant to use Newton as the name.
Further more Newton is very close to the name Norton.
Also Apple had a product long time ago name Newton.</para>

<para>Why a new file manager, isn't there already plenty of good
file managers out there for Mac? Well... what may be good for you,
isn't necessarily good for others. From a mac developers viewpoint
it must make it easier to work with lots of source files,
dotfiles, deal with permissions and reduce the need to 
do commandline operations. From a mac superusers viewpoint it
must look and feel like a native mac application. From a web developers
viewpoint it must be able to transfer files to remote sites.
Further more it must be responsive, stable and useful.</para>

<segmentedlist>
<?dbhtml list-presentation="table"?>
<segtitle>Goal</segtitle>
<segtitle>Explanation</segtitle>
<seglistitem>
	<seg>Navigation</seg>
	<seg>Norton Commander navigation. It just sticks in your brain,
		these keybindings are vital.</seg>
</seglistitem>
<seglistitem>
	<seg>Sudo</seg>
	<seg>There are areas on your computer that requires
		privileged access. Example is some of the subdirs in "/var".
		This decision have had a huge impact how the program is
		organized, so its runs as separate processes as different users.</seg>
</seglistitem>
<seglistitem>
	<seg>No beachballs</seg>
	<seg>No time out when the file system isn't responsing.</seg>
</seglistitem>
<seglistitem>
	<seg>Infographics</seg>
	<seg>Don't make me think. So you quickly can see patterns and
		irregularites, such as bad permissions, too big files,
		too small files.</seg>
</seglistitem>
</segmentedlist>

<para>Infographics wasn't really the plan to begin with. It started
as an experiment with visualizing the file sizes as sparklines and 
turned out ok. So more infographics was added.</para>

<para>Because of the complixity added by the "Sudo" and "No beachball"
goals, the plan is just to do the very basic operations:
Copy, Move, Delete. That's it. Otherwise it would take forever.
Of course more operations would be nice to have.</para>


<para>There are also some non-goals. Things that doesn't fit in at the 
moment.</para>

<segmentedlist>
<?dbhtml list-presentation="table"?>
<segtitle>Non-Goal</segtitle>
<segtitle>Explanation</segtitle>
<seglistitem>
	<seg>Tabs</seg>
	<seg>Lack of time to add support for it.</seg>
</seglistitem>
<seglistitem>
	<seg>FTP, SFTP</seg>
	<seg>There exists lots of FTP clients that makes it easier to navigate
		a remote FTP site than navigating your own computer.
		Newton Commander is about navigating your own computer.
		When that goal is reached, then maybe add FTP support.</seg>
</seglistitem>
<seglistitem>
	<seg>Icons</seg>
	<seg>Lack of time to add support for it.</seg>
</seglistitem>
</segmentedlist>

</section>

</chapter>